Hi, I'm Chris Faircloth, Artistic Director and co-owner of Salon Teez.
For those clients that like to have their hair flip out on the ends, the texturing shear is a great shear to use for this.
We'll have our teeth on the top as this will create shorter hair on the top of the hair, leaving longer hair underneath to want to flip out.
The shorter hair will actually help push into or collapse into the hair form or into the neck, creating the longer hair to flip out.
Using horizontal sections and determining where we want the flip to be, we'll simply place our shears in, the bottom blade is actually resting on my fingers.
And now I'm just using my shear, completely closing it and sliding out.
I'll do this once or twice more, just in the ends of the hair so that I create a nice flip to the ends of the hair.
I'll continue working that around the perimeter of the hair so that I get a nice even flip all the way around.
As you can see, the hair is beginning to want to flip on its own and that's exactly what we want to create there.
If they're wanting to have their hair roll under as opposed to the flip out, we'll make sure that the teeth are on the bottom and the top blade, or the straight blade is on the top.
An easy way to remember that is the teeth on the top taper, teeth on bottom blend.
So creating the roll under effect, our teeth will be on the bottom, our straight blade is on the top, and now we'll just take our shears and cut down.
This will effectively give us a nice roll to the ends of the hair but this way the shorter hair is underneath, the longer hair is on top and the longer hair will tend to, want to roll under as opposed to flip out